Mike North: 接下来我们要看的是函数和函数类型。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: The next thing we are gonna
look at is functions, and function types.
看看备忘录,
So look in the notes folder,
这个文件以数字2开头，函数基础
this is the file that starts with
the number 2, function basics
迈克 · 诺斯: 我在这里有一个函数
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So I have a function here
我和她有一个争论。
called sendEmail and
I have an argument her called to.
我在这里使用的是 HasEmail。
And what I'm using here is HasEmail.
如果我这样做，至少在 Mac，Cmd，点击,
And if I do,
at least on a Mac, Cmd, click,
这样我就可以从之前的笔记中找到这个界面。
that'll take me to this interface from the
previous notes that we were going through.
我从前面的模块导出了这个接口，并且
I exported this interface
from the previous module, and
你可以直接跳到这种类型的定义。
you can jump to
the definition of this type.
所以我会在我们进行的过程中重复使用一些东西，但是这个指出
So I'm gonna be reusing things as we
go along, but this points out that
我们可以导入和导出接口和类型，就像我们可以处理值一样。
we can import and export interfaces and
types, just like we can do with values.
这就是我们如何表示返回类型，它实际上是相同的
This is how we indicate a return type,
and it's actually the same
我们已经使用的变量约定，它是冒号后面跟着类型。
convention we've been using for
variables, It's colon followed by type.
这是一个有两个字符串的对象，接收者和主体，以及
And this is an object that has two
strings, recipient and body, and
我们只是在锻炼身体，然后发送垃圾邮件。
here we're just building up that body
to send, apparently, some spam email.
所以这是我倾向于使用类型注释的地方。
So this is a place where I tend
to always use type annotations.
这是因为我想找到这个函数的契约
And this is because I wanted to find
the contract that this function has
我程序的其他部分。
with other parts of my program.
类型脚本可以很好地推断返回类型。
Type script can infer
return types pretty well.
但是很容易犯错误
But it's very easy to slip up and
无意中改变了一些东西，我将在几分钟后演示。
unintentionally change things, which
I'll demonstrate in a couple of minutes.
这基本上就是箭头函数的味道,
This is the arrow-function flavor of,
basically,
同样的东西，唯一的区别就是你有胖箭头。
the same thing, and the only
difference is you have the fat arrows.
这就是参数列表，冒号，类型，胖箭头的实现，对吗？
So it's the parameter list, colon,
type, fat arrow implementation, right?
参数列表、冒号、类型，然后是胖箭头，您将逐渐适应它。
Parameter list, colon, type, and then the
fat arrow, and you'll get used to that.
因此，可以推断返回类型。
So, return types can be inferred.
这个函数需要一个联系人,
This is a function that
will take a contact and,
这个函数所需要的条件,
un terms of what this function needs,
它可能不仅仅只对物业名称进行操作。
it may typically operate on things that
have way more than just the property name.
但我还是保守一点,
But I'm being conservative,
就允许对任何具有属性名的对象进行操作而言。
in terms of allowing this operate on
any object that has a property name.
当我输入函数参数时，我有点想说出最小值
When I'm typing function arguments,
I kinda wanna state the minimum thing
我需要，为了避免功能过度约束，对不对？
I need, in order to avoid
over-constraining the function, right?
这可能在其他地方有用，我不想人为地强加于人
This might be useful elsewhere and
I don't want to artificially impose
关于这些论点必须是什么的附加要求。
additional requirements on
what these arguments must be.
我希望它尽可能的灵活。
I want it to be as flexible as possible.
现在的情况是,
And what's happening here is,
我们分割这个字符串，接触，名字，我们分割它的重量空间。
we split this string, contact.name,
we split it by weight space.
我们扔，如果有少于两个部分。
We throw,
if there are less than two parts.
然后我们返回一个对象，其中第一部分是名字,
And then we return an object where
the first part is the first name,
最后一部分是姓。
the last part is the last name.
如果我们只有两个部分，中间的名字最终是未定义的。
The middle name, if we only have
two parts, ends up being undefined.
或者我们把中间的所有东西都放在一起。
Or we join everything
in the middle together.
所以，如果我们看一下返回类型，就是这个。
So, if we look at the return type here,
there it is.
哎呀，我们可以看到它是正确的推断，对不对？
Oops, and we can see that it
is correctly inferred, right?
所以编译器会遍历这个程序的所有可能的路径
So the compiler's going through all
possible paths of this program, and
它正在研究回到这里的可能性。
it's figuring out what all
is possible to return here.
如果我们有这个函数,
If, instead of, so like,
let's say we have this function,
在某种程度上，我们需要处理麦当娜的案子
and, at some point,
we need to handle the Madonna case or
普林斯案，只是一个单音节词，没有姓氏。
the Prince case, where it's just
a mononym, there is no last name.
所以我们可以到这里来说如果部分长度为1,
So we would then go up here and
say If parts.length = 1,
我们可以直接回去,
instead of throwing, we can just return,
oops，return .
oops, return .
所以现在我们在这里增加了一个可能性,
So now, we've added an additional
possibility here where,
现在，我们返回一个对象，打字稿试图在这里加强一些一致性,
now, we return an object, and typescripts
try to impose some consistency here,
但是我们已经返回了一个可能有一个未定义的姓氏的东西。
but we've returned something that
potentially has an undefined last name.
事实上，所有这些值最终都是未定义的。
In fact, all of these values
will end up being undefined.
所以，我可能并不打算这样做。
So, I may not have intended
this to work in such a way.
这可能会影响我代码的其他部分。
And this may affect
other parts of my code.
所以，我想特别声明一个返回类型,
So, I like to specifically
state a return type,
因为它让我在这个职能的所有分支中保持诚实,
because it keeps me honest within
all branches of this function,
确保我的退货是有意为之。
to make sure that what I'm
returning is intentional.
你知道，有时候你会提前终止妊娠，对吧？
You know,
sometimes you early terminate, right?
如果确定刚才调用的函数，那么它现在就不是 op 了。
If you determine that this function
that was just called, it's no op now.
提前终止，这是什么意思,
And early terminating, what does that,
如果我只是说返回分号，那么我真正返回的是什么呢？
if I just say return semicolon,
what am I really returning there?
如果我调用一个函数，它只说返回，分号，我得到什么值？
If I invoke a function and it just says
return, semicolon, what value do I get?
未定义的。
Undefined.
所以，这会改变这个函数，它会改变这个类型
So, that will change what this function,
it will change the type this
函数返回，这会对你的代码产生连锁反应。
function returns, and that sort of has
a ripple effect through your code.
我宁愿保持这种刻意创造的界限,
And I would rather keep that
boundary very deliberately created,
同时对功能的内部和外部进行操作，使其正常工作。
and operate on both inside and the outside
of the function, to make things work.
迈克诺斯: 所以休息参数工作正如你所期望的,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So rest params
work just like you'd just expect,
这里没什么有趣的。
nothing really interesting here.
你唯一需要注意的就是休息参数的类型
The only thing you gotta be aware of
is the type of a rest param has to be
阵列状的。
array-like.
因为它将作为一个数组消耗。
Cuz it's gonna be consumed as an array.